# CHRISTOPHER MULVEY

Nashville Metropolitan Area, Tennessee | 850.529.0747 christopherdmulvey@gmail.com | <a href="www.linkedin.com/in/christopher-mulvey">www.linkedin.com/in/christopher-mulvey</a> | <a href="mailto:github.com/Corbec">github.com/Corbec</a> Tableau

# **SUMMARY**

Over a 21 year career with the US Navy, I became interested in the way data is handled. When an opportunity to change careers arose, I saw a chance to explore that interest and make it my new career. I am a seasoned, accomplished leader and pilot with proven expertise managing complex programs and projects serving mission-critical objectives and in support of distributed customers / stakeholders.

#### Core competencies include:

- Data Analysis with Excel(Advanced) and SQL(Postgres)
- Git and GitHub
- Agile and Kanban
- Python

- PowerBI
- Tableau
- Software and Hardware Troubleshooting
- Change and Risk Management
- Workflow and Process Redesign

# DATA ANALYST EXPERIENCE

#### Nashville Software School, Nashville, Tennessee

Apprentice Data Analyst, 9/2020 to 1/2021

- Four month full-time intensive introduction to data analytics and business intelligence processes and tools. Emphasis on analytical reasoning through hands-on training on every stage of the analytics workflow.
- Projects:
  - Tableau An exploration of World War Two bombing missions with a visualization of target locations and target types.
  - o **PowerBI** Used Formula One car racing data to explore whether engine change rules have impacted competition between the teams.
  - o **SQL** Used the Lahman baseball database to answer several questions about baseball history. Specifically looked up the World Series winners from 1970 to 2017 and computed the number of times that winner had the highest number of wins in a season.
- Tools: SQL(Postgres), Excel(Advanced), Python, PowerBI, and Tableau

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Trans States Airlines, St Louis, Missouri

Embraer 145 First Officer, 6/2018 to 4/2020

• Embraer 145 First Officer for a regional airline based at Chicago O'Hare International Airport.

**US Navy**, 5/1997 to 8/2018

Leonardo, New Jersey

Senior Operations Manager, 10/2015 to 7/2018

- Serving as Commanding Officer, oversaw Navy Operational Support Center Earle and a staff of 17 supporting 230 Navy Selected Reservists.
- Responsible for \$700K annual budget, as well as security and maintenance of 3 Navy Operational Support Center Earle facilities, and 2 vehicles.
- Managed all staff and Reservist training and medical readiness requirements, including 20-30 annual training requirements. Identified units and members that were lagging in training through regular reports. Adjusted training accordingly to ensure requirements were completed.
- Ensured information security and policy / regulatory compliance, including HIPAA and PII.
- Seamlessly planned, orchestrated, and oversaw 12 annual Reserve weekends, coordinated travel, lodging, and meals for 100-200 Reservists; scheduled all training sessions and speakers, tracked completed training requirements, processed travel expense claims, and managed Reserve duty payroll.
- Improved command performance and morale after previous Commanding Officer was relieved, garnering improved scores for command climate surveys.

## Millington, Tennessee

Program Manager, 2/2014 to 9/2015

- Directed \$35M Active Duty for Special Work (ADSW) Program within Navy Personnel Command, leading team of 6 order writers, as well as an officer and a civilian employee, in production of 1.5K official orders per year. Regularly worked with widely distributed organizations to define staffing requirements and clarify official orders.
- Played instrumental role in command-level business process reengineering initiative; spearheaded overhaul of ADSW governing instruction. Lead transition from paper-based to electronic workflows within the ADSW program.

#### Atlanta, Georgia

Senior Operations Manager, 9/2011 to 2/2014

- As Executive Officer, directed team of 37 within Navy Operational Support Center Atlanta in service delivery to 1.5K Navy Selected Reservists
- Served as second in command, managing daily command-wide administration, operations, resource planning / allocation, and communications.

# **EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS**

## **Data Analytics Boot Camp**

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL, Nashville, Tennessee, January 2021

# **Master of Science in Information Technology Project Management**

UNIVERSITY OF MARYLAND UNIVERSITY COLLEGE, Adelphi, Maryland, Attended 2016 - 2017

 Suspended to pursue airline career; Considering change in focus to Informatics or Database Management

# **Bachelor of Science in Computer Information Systems**

NORWICH UNIVERSITY, Northfield, Vermont, May 1997

Security Clearance: Secret (out of scope 2/2018)

Licensure & Certification: CompTIA A+, Network+, and Security+ Certifications

Professional Development: US Navy Flight School – fixed & rotary wing

*Non-technical skills:* Customer and Stakeholder Relations | Standards, Regulatory and Policy Compliance | Team Building, Mentoring and Leadership | Program / Project Management Strategies